<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Binary Strolls]]></title>
  <link href="http://dbalan.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dbalan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-01T11:56:26+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://dbalan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dhananjay Balan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Random rant]]></title>
    <link href="http://dbalan.github.io/blog/2015/12/01/a-random-rant/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://dbalan.github.io/blog/2015/12/01/a-random-rant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><code>
/me sets +rant
</code>
Yesterday, Found an old portable hard disk in the attic. Face lights up. Connect to computer, doesnt work. The connection probabaly fried. Its probabaly the connector, HDD internally uses a <code>SATA</code> bus.</p>

<p>I know what to do, lets oopen the server box and connect to the motherboard. Can’t find any SATA cable. <code>find sata ~house</code></p>

<p>Finally hard disk plugged in, <code>FreeBSD</code> boots. <code>dmesg</code> shows everything is alright, except <code>ext4</code>. #sigh</p>

<p>Somebody suggests <code>fuse</code>. Alright, thats it then. Compile, <code>kldld</code> and booyeah!</p>

<p>Okay, its full of photos from past. Wow! I need to see them, lets share it to something with a monitor. That’d be my mac. <code>sshfs</code>? Sorry dude, you need the whole <code>XCode</code> suite and should sacrifice an extra kidney to load unsigned <code>kext</code>s.</p>

<p>But there are other ways of sharing files. <code>SMB</code> FTW!</p>

<p>Why the fuck are there three samba versions in ports. <code>cd /usr/ports/samba$(random_ver)</code></p>

<p>Okay, samba is setup and mounted, tears</p>

<p>Nooo &ndash; I can’t access the hard disk. Why? huh perms fucking perms!</p>

<p>I got this! gonna chmod the shit out, but except… it doesn’t work. What the fuck does not implemented mean?</p>

<p>JFGI. JFGI POints to ext4 code &ndash; ext4 fuse is strictly read only. (facepalm)</p>

<p>Story still continues…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
